MYLES GRAY

PROFILE

I have considerable experience researching, designing, operating and supporting enterprise IT solutions, from both end customer and service provider sides.

Strong public speaker, very natural to talk and give seminars in front of groups - formally and informally - and I interact very well with individuals.

I have a very strong interest in new technologies, from virtualisation and SDN to home automation - particularly focused on the VMware SDDC stack for virtualisation, networking and SDS, but not limited to it.

My technical experience coupled with my solution design experience help me relate business requirements to technical and design decisions to deliver as best as is possible for every case.

EXPERIENCE

BLOGGER, BLAH, CLOUD - 03/2012 - PRESENT

I write articles on challenges I face, solutions I find and interesting design/implementation problems I come across on my personal site: https://blah.cloud

NOVOSCO, CLOUD TECHNOLOGIST - 10/2016 - PRESENT

R&D for public cloud based service design, customer pre-sales engagements, educational sales oriented webinars for customers and consulting on VMware and networking infrastructures for large MSP customers.

NOVOSCO, INFRASTRUCTURE ENGINEER - 08/2014 - 10/2016

I worked in the Hosted Platforms division, a small team where we stood up, operationalised and handed over dedicated infrastructures and cloud platforms for our MSP customers.

Scripting, automation through PowerShell and PowerCLI, AWS lambda and public cloud services all part of the gig.

Work daily with EMC SANs, Cisco IOS and Nexus switching, blade chassis and whole VMware SDDC suite (NSX, vCloud Director, ESXi, vCenter, VSAN) as well as partner solutions (Zerto, Veeam, et al.)

Responsible for Novosco "STC" (Single Tenant Cloud) - A new scale-out bare metal IaaS platform based on vSAN - design, implementation, operational handovers and financial modelling under my remit. More info here: https://blah.cloud/featured/

EXITEX LTD, NETWORK & VIRTUALISATION ADMIN - 05/2012 - 08/2014

Responsible for mission critical networking and virtualisation infrastructure redesign, backup/redundancy system design.

Expansion solutions implemented including microwave links for remote premises, site-to-site VPNs and a move from single subnet/VLAN per-site to fully routed core/edge network.

EDUCATION

QUEEN'S UNIVERSITY BELFAST - BSC , BUSINESS I.T - 2013

Graduated on a 2-1 with Honours, Awarded best final year project in Technology and Business field by PwC.

ABBEY GRAMMAR SCHOOL - 2009

A-Levels - Physics - A, Technology and Design (Systems and Control) - A, Mathematics - B

CERTIFICATIONS

VMWARE

Working towards VCDX-DCV. Current holder of: VCIX6-NV, VCAP6-NV Deploy, VCP6-DCV, VCP5-DCV

CISCO

CCNA R&S, CCENT R&S

OTHER

Zerto ZCP, PernixPrime

AWARDS

VMware vExpert 2016-17, vExpert VSAN, vExpert NSX, PernixPro, Nutanix NTC

PUBLICATIONS

Blah, Cloud - Blog: https://blah.cloud

vSphere Pocket Designbook v3 - Book: https://blah.cloud/?p=1967

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

Climbing is a huge passion of mine, it leads me to many new places, countries and allows me to meet some amazing people and indulge in my other favourite hobbies - photography and cinematography. I have a penchant for car racing.

REFERENCES

James Montgomery - Novosco Ltd, HSP SDM - <u>james.montgomery@novosco.com</u>

Adrian Gray - Exitex, Director - adrian.gray@exitex.co.uk